<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<transcript id="23376" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2004 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2004-04-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nancy Paxton, Senior Director of Corporate Finance and Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Fred Anderson, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Peter Oppenheimer, Vice President of Finance</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everyone, and welcome to the Apple Computer conference call to discuss second quarter financial results.  Today's call is being recorded.  At this time for opening remarks, introductions, I would like to turn the call over to the Senior Director of Investor Relations and Corporate Finance, Ms. Nancy Paxton.  Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good afternoon and thanks to everyone for joining us today.  Speaking today are Apple CFO, Fred Anderson; and SVP of Finance, Peter Oppenheimer; and they will be joined by EVP of Sales and Operations, Tim Cook; as well as VP and Corporate Treasurer, Gary Wipfler for the Q&amp;A session with the analysts.  Please note that some of the information you will hear during this call consists of forward-looking statements regarding revenue, gross margin, operating expenses, executive compensation, restructuring expense, other income and expense, taxes, Apple's retail initiatives, capital expenditures and earnings per share.  Actual results or trends could differ materially from our forecast.  For more information please refer to pages 30 through 39 of Apple's latest Form 10-Q for the quarter ended December 27th, 2003.</p>
          <p>Please also note that should non-GAAP financial measures be included in today's call, such information should be viewed in addition to, and not in lieu of, Apple's GAAP results.  While we don't anticipate providing non-GAAP measures other than those included in the earnings press release, should we provide others, a reconciliation of the GAAP and non-GAAP measures will be posted on Apple's website at www.apple.com/investor.  In connection with SEC rules on corporate disclosure, Apple is making this analyst call open to the media and general public by broadcasting this call over the internet and with that I'd like to turn the call over to Fred Anderson for introductory remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nancy.  We are exceptionally pleased with the results of the March quarter for a number of reasons.  Apple achieved very strong year-over-year revenue growth of 29% for the quarter and 33% for the first half of the fiscal year.  This revenue growth is being driven by a much more diversified portfolio of hardware, software, and service products than we have delivered in the past, as well as expanded distribution through the channel and our online and retail stores.  More importantly, our results demonstrate operating margin expansion.  Excluding restructuring charges, operating margin was 3.2% for the March quarter and 3.5% for the first half of the fiscal year, demonstrating the leverage in Apple's financial model that we can achieve as we grow revenue.  It is clear that the investments that we have made over the past few years in research and development and in our retail initiative are paying off.</p>
          <p>As most of you know, I will be retiring as Apple's CFO on June 1st.  It has been a real privilege for me to be Apple's CFO over the past eight years, and I look forward to staying involved with Apple after my retirement.  Peter Oppenheimer who has done an outstanding job as Apple's corporate comptroller will be taking over as CFO and I'd like to turn the call over to him now for more details on the second quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fred.  As Fred mentioned, revenue of $1.909 billion was up 29% year over year.  This represents our third consecutive quarter of double-digit revenue growth and our strongest March quarter in four years.  Net income was 46 million, or 12 cents per diluted share.  These GAAP results include an after-tax restructuring charge of 7 million, or 2 cents per diluted share for severance costs related to the closing of our Sacramento manufacturing operation and reductions in sales and marketing staff.  We sold over 749,000 Macintosh units and 807,000 iPods during the quarter representing a 5% increase in CPU units and more than 10 times the number of iPods shipped in the year-ago quarter.  CPU revenue was up 6% while iPod revenue was up over 750%.  In Q2, our 29% revenue growth was driven by our diversified portfolio of products, with iPod contributing about half the growth and all other products and services contributing the balance.  Panther continued to sell well in its second quarter and we were very pleased with the reception of iLife '04 in its first quarter.</p>
          <p>Ending channel inventory units declined by 10% and remained within our target range of four to five weeks.  The net decline in inventory was attributable to the PowerBook and the PowerMac product families.  In terms of products, portables represented 48% of all Macintosh systems sold during the quarter led by the iBook at 201,000 units and PowerBook at 157,000 units.  PowerMac shipments were up, and iMac shipments were 217,000 units.  There were two factors that impacted the number of PowerMacs shipped.  First, we reduced the PowerMac channel inventory so reported unit sell-in was less than sell-through.  Second, we were delayed in shipping the G5 until the last week of the third quarter and exited March with most of the quarter's orders still in backlog.  We had a phenomenal quarter for iPods, shipping a record 807,000 units, exceeding the prior holiday quarter record of 733,000 units.  Continued momentum of the iPod combined with the introduction of the iPod mini in the U.S. and retail distribution points now in excess of 12,000 worldwide drove the healthy 10% sequential increase.  Apple moved the worldwide availability of iPod mini to July due to the strong demand in the U.S. that far exceeded the total planned supply through the end of June.  iPod remains the number one selling MP3 player according to the latest data available from NPD Tech World.  iPod and the iTunes Music Store continue to distinguish themselves from the competition and have market-leading positions.  We expect our strong momentum to continue as we catch up with iPod mini demand and as HP launches their digital music player this summer.</p>
          <p>The Apple retail stores continue to deliver outstanding results.  We opened five stores during the quarter, including the San Francisco flagship store, bringing the quarter end total to 78.  Apple retail store revenue was 266 million, almost double the level of the year-ago quarter and only 7 million below the December quarter.  With an average of 75 stores open during the quarter, average quarterly revenue per store was 3.5 million, up from 2.6 million in the year-ago quarter.  The retail stores also contributed 5 million in segment profit during the quarter and 45 million in additional manufacturing margin.  Traffic was very strong during the quarter with 5.7 million people visiting our retail stores, translating into 5.8 thousand visitors per store per week.  This compares to 6,000 visitors per store per week in the December quarter and 4.4 thousand visitors per store per week in the year-ago quarter.  We plan to continue to add stores that can achieve strong sales and profitability during their first year of operation.  We expect to open an additional 10 stores during the balance of fiscal '04 and end the fiscal year with approximately 88 stores.</p>
          <p>We are also very excited to announce the expected opening of our store in London before the end of the calendar year.  Results from our U.S. education channel were particularly encouraging.  Overall, CPU units grew 10% year-over-year, which was over three times the latest IDC market growth estimate.  Revenue was even more impressive at 18% year-over-year growth.  Higher education drove the growth with over 40% year-over-year revenue growth for the second quarter in a row.  These results give us reason to be optimistic as we head into the back-to-school season later this year.  Our K-12 business was relatively flat year-over-year as some districts continue to be challenged by budget constraints.  We did see increases in the number of one-to-one implementations during the quarter versus last year, which drove a marked increase in iBook sales.  We continue to believe that our focus on student achievement and learning outcomes positions Apple uniquely in this market.</p>
          <p>In terms of geographic performance, revenue in Europe was up 33% year-over-year while revenue in the Americas, excluding the retail segment, was up 29%.  Combining the Americas segment results with U.S. sales from the retail segment, yields a year-over-year increase of 39%.  Revenue in the Japan segment was down 21% year-over-year.  Gross margin was 27.8%, up 110 basis points from the prior quarter and slightly exceeding our guidance of 27 1/2%.  The sequential increase in gross margin was a function of a better commodity pricing environment and more typical warranty expense and product transitions relative to Q1.  Excluding a restructuring charge of 10 million, OPEX was 468 million, 8 million higher than expected, primarily due to variable selling expenses associated with higher than expected revenue.</p>
          <p>On March 24th, Apple's Board of Directors granted restricted stock units to company's senior management, excluding the CEO.  The Board believes that basing the majority of executives' pay on equity is the best way to align management's interests with shareholders' interests.  The restricted stock units will vest over four years.  The board views these RSUs as important means of retaining key executives and does not anticipate making additional grants to these executives during their four-year timeframe.  Like restricted stock, the value of these RSUs must be amortized through the income statement and will add an additional 3.8 million in compensation expense per quarter going forward until fully vested.  In addition, over the next two years we will continue to recognize quarterly amortization expense of approximately 6.25 million related to the restricted stock previously granted to the CEO.  OI&amp;E was 12 million, 2 million better than guidance primarily due to interest and dividend income.  The tax rate for the quarter was 28% as expected.</p>
          <p>In terms of the balance sheet, cash was 4.594 billion, down just 197 million sequentially despite the 300 million senior debt retirement on February 17th that has left us debt-free.  The strong cash profile reflects continued strong asset management and contributions from operating income.  Total capital expenditures for the quarter were 35 million, including 20 million for our retail initiative.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to the June quarter, I'd like to review our outlook which includes the types of forward-looking information that Nancy referred to at the beginning of the call.  For the June quarter, we expect our fourth consecutive quarter of year-over-year double-digit growth in both revenue and earnings.  We are targeting revenue of about 1.925 billion.  We expect GAAP diluted earnings per share of 12 to 13 cents, which includes approximately 10 million or 2 cents per diluted share in additional expected restructuring charges, primarily related to finalizing the closing of our Sacramento manufacturing operation.  We expect gross margin to be relatively flat sequentially at about 28%.  We expect OPEX to be about 480 million, including the previously mentioned 10 million restructuring charge and 10 million in executive compensation amortization.  We expect OME to be about 12 million and we expect the tax rate to be 28%.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we expect fiscal '04 capital expenditures to be about 190 million, including 110 million associated with the retail initiative.  With that, I'd like to open the call to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir.  Today's question-and-answer session will be conducted electronically.  If you care to ask a question, please signal by pressing the star key, followed by the digit "1" on your touchtone telephone.  If you are using a speakerphone, please make sure that your mute function is turned off to make sure our equipment can read your signal.  We will come to you in the order that you signal and will take as many questions as time permits.  Again that is "star," "1" to ask a question on today's call and we'll pause for just a moment to assemble our roster.  We'll take our first question from Steve Milunovich with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.  Two topics.  First of all, can you talk about distribution and you mentioned the online effort and so forth.  I don't know if you can talk about how much success you feel you are having outside the stores, both online and in other retail centers and apparently you had a pilot with Best Buy going on which may have been pulled back.  I wonder if you can comment on that.  And second on the iPod side, can you talk about the gross margin on iPod and where it is today and if you still expect it's going to be coming down to 20%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I will address a little bit of your online and direct questions and take the iPod gross margin and leave Best Buy and some of the other distribution topics to Tim.  Let me start with the iPod gross margin.  As we indicated last quarter, the iPod gross margin was about our corporate average of 27%.  This quarter, it was about 23% as we began to ship the iPod mini, and we still anticipate the gross margin being about 20% as we more fully ramp the iPod mini and begin to ship units to HP.</p>
          <p>In terms of online, we continue to do extremely well there.  We're up very strong year over year, as well as all of our direct markets.  Our direct sales in the quarter were 42% of total sales, and we define that as sales to U.S. education, online and through our retail stores, and that compares to 35% in the year-ago quarter.  Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, on your question on distribution, we're continuing to expand the number of places that we have iPod from the beginning of Q1 through the beginning of last October, we've now raised that from 8,000 to 12,000.  So we've increased about 50%.  About 80% of that expansion was outside the U.S. because we felt we fundamentally did not have enough spots.  I would tell you that we're continuing to look for more quality channels and anticipate growing that more as we step through the year and so on the Best Buy in particular, Best Buy continues to be a very key iPod channel for us.  They also continue to sell CPUs in a &#x2013; in some number of the stores.  The pilot that you referenced had run its natural course and so at this point we're analyzing the data to conclude what to do moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any comment on future expected sales for iPod, and do you have any evidence or expect to see kind of the halo effect of the iPod success turn into more PC business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not going to provide guidance for future iPod shipments except to say in the third quarter, we expect to be very constrained and hope to catch up and balance supply and demand in the fourth quarter.  We are hearing anecdotal stories all the time, both in our retail stores and through the channel where people have &#x2013; Windows users have purchased the iPod, have used it, the Music Store, and have come in and either switched to the Mac or added a Mac to their computers at home.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, ma'am.  That comes from Joel Wagonfeld with First Albany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.  I was wondering if you could comment a little bit further on the PowerMac volumes.  They were a little bit below what you had stated was your goal and I think what myself and others had expected.  You mentioned some inventory reduction, but you had done that last quarter and you had also mentioned last quarter that you intended to be relatively aggressive in terms of price drive share there.  So I'm wondering if you could just give us a little more color on the pricing dynamics and the upgrade, uptake that you've seen and whether the 200,000 target is now obsolete or if you are sticking with that and the timeframe is just a little bit longer.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our PowerMac sell in the quarter was 174,000 units and that was impacted by two factors.  The first is we, as I indicated, reduced our total channel inventory by about 10%, and the PowerMac line saw the largest component of that.  We also were delayed in shipping the Xserve G5 until the last week of the quarter.  So virtually all of the units that we sold were in our backlog.  So when you account or add those two things back, our true sales on the PowerMac line were over 190,000 in the quarter.</p>
          <p>As regards our 200,000 unit objective, we still think in some quarters, we'll be above that and some quarters we'll be a little bit below, just depending upon seasonality and where we are in the product life cycle.  Tim, do you want to add anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just add a couple of things to that, Joel.  One is that the mix of G5 that we're selling is substantially richer than the mix historically that we saw in G4 and as we understand the market level, what is happening is that our video customers are adopting G5 very, very quickly, they value the performance of G5, the apps are all ported and we're doing amazingly well in that market.</p>
          <p>At the other end of the spectrum, the D&amp;P customer is much slower to adopt.  In some geographies as &#x2013; like Japan as an example, QuarkXPress is not ported yet.  That obviously affects the level of adoption and the speed of adoption in the D&amp;P sector.  I do, however, think that gives us a great opportunity moving forward.  And sort of the middle of that spectrum, the education market is adopting it very well and so the markets net/net are all over the board.  I think they &#x2013; our greatest opportunity moving forward is to speed up the adoption in D&amp;P.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is no fundamental change in your thought about the adoption curve or the potential rate?  It's just some gives and takes on each side of it that are affecting the timing of the trajectory of this cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good characterization.  Basically, if you think about the same markets I told you about in video, that market economically is very healthy.  The broadcasters have money, they are spending money.  On the other end of that spectrum, on the D&amp;P sector, that market is still economically challenged.  They are at the front end of this recovery curve but, you know, I think that bodes well for the future is the positive way to look at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I would add these segments are also going portable as well, adding PowerBooks into the mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Congratulations on a great quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, y'all.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Richard Gardner with Smith Barney.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  Peter, on the gross margin guidance, you talked about gross margin being pretty flat sequentially in the second calendar quarter.  Seems like there are a couple of headwinds at the gross line.  The iPod gross margin should continue to trend down.  It sounds like you might have some product transitions at the high end of the product line.  And also, perhaps maybe, you know, a slowdown, further slowdown in Mac OS X upgrade revenue.  Just wondering if you can help us understand why you think the gross margins will remain flat in the June quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that we will continue to see a positive commodity cost environment that plays into it.  I think our software sales will continue to be strong in our June quarter.  They won't be at the level of what we saw in the December quarter as Panther enters its third quarter, but it and iLife are doing incredibly well and we also continue to do well in our direct sales which plays well into our gross margin story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And another question, if I could.  There have been some rumblings recently of problems with iPod mini in terms of static potentially related to the connection between the headphone jack and the motherboard on the device.  I know you probably can't comment at this point but just curious if you have any statement to make there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich, we're highly confident with the minis that we're shipping.  We've seen some of those reports.  They are isolated online reports.  We're investigating those because we want to very much understand those, but I would tell you that the number of complaints that we've had from customers through our AppleCare tech support is extremely small.  However, anyone that's listening to the call that has a problem, please call the AppleCare because we want to take care of the issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I'm going to sneak one more in, if I could, and that is on Xserve G5, are you happy with the supply of chips that you are getting from your major partner, and when do you expect to be caught up with that backlog?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Rich, as Peter talked about, in analyzing the PowerMac sell-in for the quarter, we shipped very, very few Xserve G5s last quarter.  That was not a demand issue.  It was a supply issue.  So obviously we were not happy with the deliveries that we got.  However, IBM is working very, very hard to bring the supply/demand in balance, and we're confident that we will get there during the current quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rich.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Ben Reitzes with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.  A couple of questions with regard to iPod.  Could you talk about the drive availability a little bit?  You said you are going to be constrained.  Could you talk about when you feel that you can be comfortable with your suppliers in both levels, the regular iPods and the iPod mini and also talk about with regard to products, new products in general, is everything that you feel coming, has anything slipped that perhaps on the new product side or do you still feel that you have a very robust product cycle coming?  I know you don't give details, but is everything still on track with your previous expectations and do you feel &#x2013; still feel you have a robust product cycle coming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll address the, sort of the questions on the product cycle and leave the iPod mini supply question to Tim.  As you indicated, we're not going to get into telling you what our future products are but we have all of our transitions, how many we think we can make, factored into our guidance and are comfortable with that at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, let me start with the white iPod.  The iPod is in reasonable supply/demand balance in every geography right now, and that took us a while to get there because of the intense demand, but it's in reasonably good balance today.  On the mini, it is not in balance.  As you saw a few weeks ago, we've extended our international launch until July.  We did that because demand was far exceeding the supply that we had previously planned across the quarter.  My current view is that that &#x2013; that we will reach a supply/demand balance during our fiscal Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the calendar 3Q, you feel you can be there.  Is that &#x2013; do you think you need to procure new sources for the iPod mini, or are you all set with the current supplier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will do whatever it takes to attempt to get into supply/demand balance.  I wouldn't want to go into our specific plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With regard to the retail stores that you mentioned that you had $5 million in profit, and could you just talk about how that plays out sequentially throughout the year with the plan?  Is there any reason to &#x2013; not to assume that that gets markedly better each quarter, at least by a few million, and how should we be thinking about how the profitability of that area plays out throughout the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm not going to get into providing a specific guidance for Q3 or beyond at the retail segment level.  However, I will tell you that Ron has really focused on growing the top and bottom line of our retail initiative.  He is really trying to drive productivity into our existing stores and is focused to opening new stores that will be profitable in the first year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then one last thing, if I could sneak it in.  Obviously we've seen pretty strong results from Adobe recently with their Creative Suite, and how would you characterize the state of the creative professional market right now and the state of the economy with regard to your creative customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll make an opening comment and then Tim can add on.  As regards the Adobe Creative Suite, that's a product that's doing well for them.  It's growing quickly, but it represents about 15% of their total revenue.  It requires Mac OS X to run.  That's one of the reasons why we think we continue to do so well with Panther, but it runs not only on G5s, but also G4s and PowerBooks, and we think that customers are not only upgrading to G5s but also PowerBooks to run it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You think that benefit continues into the current quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to add anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would just add two things to that.  If you look at our pro product, the PowerBook and the PowerMac, if you look at those products, '03 to '02 &#x2013; fiscal year '03 to '02 &#x2013; we grew 13%.  Over the first half of '04, we've grown 26% and so that would indicate that those products are very, very strong, you know, with accelerating growth.  I would say once again that if you look at the spectrum of creative customers that we have, the video customer, very, very strong.  On the other end of the spectrum, D&amp;P, the more traditional design and publishing market, magazines, newspapers, et cetera, that market is slow to adopt.  The apps are slower to getting there to ten in some of the geographies.  However, again, I do view that that's an excellent opportunity for us moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dan.  Could we have another question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Shannon Cross with Cross Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, guys.  A follow-up on the Xserve question: is IBM the only supply constraint or component issue that you guys are stating with the Xserve in terms of your delays?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of, I think you said you expect to catch up during this quarter.  So do you feel they are now ramped up to full production on the 90 nanometer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I feel that we are ramping to full production across the course of the quarter and that prior to the quarter's close that we would be at a supply/demand balance based on our current view of demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then I had a different question on iTunes actually.  We've noticed that on some of your albums like the most popular ones, you've started to price above $10 and I'm just curious as if you guys see yourselves developing some pricing power with iTunes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we &#x2013; we are pricing our &#x2013; most of our albums at $9.99.  We are vastly more competitive than what you would see out there, especially from Amazon and other physical distributors of CDs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But your &#x2013; you have, you have priced some of them a bit higher; is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are charged a bit more from some of the labels on some of the albums and they are priced accordingly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the vast majority are &#x2013; of the albums are at $9.99 and a vast majority of the songs are at 99 cents.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then finally with regard to your iPod numbers, can you give us some idea of the breakdown between, you know, the white iPod and your iPod mini in terms of the 800,000 you sold during the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.  For competitive reasons, we're not going to break out the mini from the iPod.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Then just, I guess was there any change in sort of the mix of traditional iPods during the quarter so we can kind of back into it, or did you sort of sell the same kind of mix you've been selling historically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a bit of a mixdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Shannon.  Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go now to Rebecca Runkle with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks.  Just a couple of questions and a follow-up on Shannon's, if I may just ask it slightly differently just to make sure I understand and that is, can you comment about the degree of cannibalization that you saw within the white iPod with the introduction of the minis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Rebecca, it's Tim.  It's very difficult to answer that question because the supply has been so constrained versus what the demand is on the mini.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, our current view is that we have seen very minimal.  However, with a lot more supply, we might have a different view.  So, you know, right now, very little.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...which makes sense.  And then any update in terms of number of songs sold as it relates to iTunes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of weeks ago, we released that we have sold our 50 millionth song and we will provide updates from time to time as we cross major milestones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  And then last question.  As it relates to Japan, you obviously &#x2013; you know, last year was difficult.  You saw some sequential stability in Japan.  Can you just comment on how Japan fared relative to your internal expectations, especially within the context of the new store opening?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me say a couple of things about Japan, Rebecca.  If you look back, you talked about last year.  In September and December quarters from IDC, IDC shows that we actually gained share in Japan year-over-year in both of those quarters.  I don't have the March numbers yet.  Obviously that will occur sometime after.  However, looking at our March results, the &#x2013; there's a couple of points I should make in your analysis of those.  One thing is that half of the year-over-year decline in units is due to a channel inventory adjustment in Japan.  Secondly, the Ginza store that you referenced is not included in the Japan line that you see.  It's included in our retail segment.  And so when you take both of these into account, the reduction year-over-year is materially less than what you have on the sheet there.</p>
          <p>Now, having said all of that, I am not happy with our results in Japan, and we've got a number of activities underway to make those results better.  I mentioned before, and I'll just briefly mention this again, is that some of the apps &#x2013; like QuarkXpress is one of them in our key D&amp;P sector &#x2013; is not ported yet in Japan.  However, the current view is that that would happen during a later part of the current quarter and so a number of things going on to improve our results there.  How we compare to market for March, I don't really know.  That market is not a great growing market just now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But clearly you would expect the sequential performance throughout the year to improve in Japan, given the initiatives you already have underway and those that are coming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am putting personally a lot of energy into Japan, as many people are in Apple, and we absolutely expect it to improve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wonderful.  And I just &#x2013; good luck, Fred, it's been great working with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rebecca.  Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go now to Keith Bachman with Banc of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a couple, if I could.  First off, the iBook numbers were better at least than I was expecting.  Can you talk a little bit about what was going on there in terms of the unit growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we could not have been happier with iBook.  It was 201,000 in the second quarter, and I would like to point out, that was about the same number we saw in December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did not see a seasonal decline.  We came out in October with the iBook upgrading it to a G4.  It has been met with great customer response.  And the quarter that we had, both in December and March, was the second biggest quarter in the company's history for iBook, doing very well in consumer and in education.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that upgrade process still being felt here, post the quarter close?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're not going to give any, you know, specific early results in Q3, but if Q2 was any indication, it's quite positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  You mentioned that the margin, the gross margin, was a little better than you thought, even as iPod margins were going down.  What was the delta on the margin side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really two things.  Slightly better commodity environment than we had anticipated, and we did a bit better in software, particularly in iLife '04.  Customer reception was just fabulous, and we sold over 400,000 copies on a standalone basis, not including those that were bundled on the CPUs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then is there any kind of correlation or thought process we should be thinking about if direct sales are going up, if they were 42% this quarter versus 35, I think you said year-ago quarter, what are the margin implications of that, if that keeps moving?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's really two or three things that will generally be accretive to our margin as we go forward, and one area that I think would go down.  Our direct sales, when we sell directly, we sell really at the street price.  We trap the channel margin.  We also tend to sell a richer mix when we sell direct than we sell through the channel.  So both of those things are good for margin.  And our software portfolio and accessories continues to broaden quarter after quarter, and those carry good margins as well.  So those are the things that are generally accretive to margins.</p>
          <p>The hardware environment is very competitive, and we are being as competitive there as we feel necessary to continue our growth, and that would be an offset to the couple of positives that I laid out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just so I'm clear, you mentioned three.  I only, for whatever reason, caught two:  Software portfolio --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Software portfolio, going more direct, and then selling up a line and attaching more while selling direct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gotcha.  Okay.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Keith.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Bill Fearnley with FTN Midwest Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  A couple of questions on the Apple stores.  Do you have any preliminary metrics on the focus on small-to-medium business in your seminar activities that you undertook here in the calendar first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is just an estimate, but we would estimate that in the second quarter, 13% of our sales were to small and medium business.  We would estimate that that was up from 5% in the year-ago quarter and 10% in the holiday quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Another channels question as well.  Tim had briefly mentioned, earlier in the call in response to another question, that you were &#x2013; that he was looking at expanding channels and I was wondering if you could give more details on that, if it's iPod focused, Macintosh focused, U.S. or international, if there are any other details you could provide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, the specific comment I had made earlier is that we had expanded the iPods from 8,000 storefronts worldwide to 12,000 as we ended this past quarter, Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I also said that we would continue to expand that channel because we want it in every good selling location</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the channel expansion would be more iPod-focused then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are always looking for channel expansion for the Mac as well, but obviously not to those kinds of numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And one last question, if I could, regarding higher ed strength.  Was that with institutions and student buys as well?  If you could provide some more details, that would be great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The strength was in both institutional and individual, yes, and picking up on the portable point that Peter made, if you cross the PowerBook and iBook, our portables in higher ed were up over 50% last quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And was that mostly student purchase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a &#x2013; again, combination of student and institutional purchase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Congratulations to Fred as well.  Thank you, folks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bill.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Charles Wolf with Needham and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  I want to circle back to a question that Steve Milunovich asked.  Do you plan to attempt to quantify the ability of the iPod, for example, to increase the number of switchers from the Windows to the Mac platform?  Is there any metrics that we can look at that might help us quantify that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; there really aren't.  We have an idea of the Windows versus Mac sales, but we're not going to release that for competitive reasons.  It's hard to measure it, especially through the channel when we don't control the point of sale, but with the number of just anecdotal stories that we're hearing about people that are either switching or adding Macs to their homes and businesses is increasing over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, do you think it's possible that the strong iBook quarter might reflect switchers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Absolutely.  I also think upgrades to &#x2013; you know, to the G4 chip as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, when does HP plan to ship the so-called hPod?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Charlie, we still plan to begin shipping the HP in the summer.  I would point out that HP is already downloading iTunes on a number of units that they are shipping and, in fact, over 300,000 have already shipped.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Charlie.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Michelle Gutierrez with Schwab Soundview.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I wanted to ask.  Did you guys provide the operating income by geography?  Because I couldn't find that anywhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have not provided that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is something you've provided in the past.  Is this something that you are not going to provide any longer? S</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will provide that when we file our 10Q.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  On the iPods, the iPod mini in particular where you are seeing the capacity constraint, is it &#x2013; is there any items in particular where you guys are particularly in tight supply, are there any other components or is it a manufacturing constraint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's &#x2013; Michelle, there's no manufacturing constraint at all.  It is a component constraint.  I'd rather not go into the details of that.  The most important thing is that we're working very hard to balance supply and demand in fiscal Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For fiscal Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And along the same lines as the iPod and the iPod mini, you know, just from testimonials it seems like you guys are offering a free upgrade from the iPod mini to the 15 gig iPod for customers who have to wait.  It seems like there's almost a six-week wait time at this point.  Have you seen any uptake on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're &#x2013; that's actually not an offer that is generally available.  For a few customers that we quoted a date and then could not achieve it, we gave them an option to do that at their election, but it's a very small number of customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And, you know, along with the iTunes, you know, the Pepsi, the Pepsi advertising campaign, can you give us an update on how that had closed out?  Because I know that it had run a little bit behind expectations because of a slow turnover in terms of the stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're very happy with the progress that we've made on the Music Store and the customer reception to date, and I think we'll be getting an update a little closer to our one-year anniversary and might include some comments on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you very much.  Great quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Thanks, Michelle.  Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Howard Gleicher with Metropolitan West.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you.  Fred and Peter, I'm looking at the balance sheet without having the cash flow statement unfortunately in front of me.  It looks like the improvement in cash during the quarter was just north of $300 million as total cash, equivalent, short-term investments, including the reduction of debt, and it looks like working capital was maybe about a wash or something like that.  Is that about right, and is &#x2013; and it seems like a very high number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, our actual cash balance, as I said in the preamble, declined by about $200 million as a result of our paying off on February 17th our 300 million in debt.  We had a strong cash conversion cycle in the quarter.  I believe it was 35 days.  DSO was 28 days, and inventory days were 4.  So we were quite pleased with our working capital management and actually very happy that our cash balance declined quite a bit less than the debt repayment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't want to mix, mix terms, but your short-term investments, which I guess I'm just also calling cash, was up by $266 million.  So shouldn't you add that to the original figure that you gave me for a true cash generating ability during the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When I refer to our cash at $4.594 billion, that included our cash and short-term investments.  Gary, do you want to --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that summarized it pretty well.  That we were looking at it the same way you were.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay.  I'll follow up.  I'll follow up further.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Howard.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Rob Cihra with Fulcrum Global Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks very much.  A few questions, if that's all right.  One on the retail store.  You guys mentioned 88 being a target now by the end of the fiscal year and I believe your old target was 80.  Is that right and can you say what prompted that, or is that just simply the fact that stores are going well so you've increased the number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we increased from 80, which we had said we would have by the back-to-school season by the &#x2013; to 88 by the end of the fiscal year.  The retail initiative is going very well.  We're opening about 25 stores each year.  By getting to 88 this fiscal year, that will put us at 23 for the fiscal year; and in terms of the increase from 80 to 88, Ron and his real estate executives were able to secure some great sites that we had planned to open in the December quarter that we will open over the summer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And if I can just ask a broader question on your unit growth.  If you look &#x2013; not to take away clearly from the phenomenal success of the iPod, but if you look at your core Mac units, they are only up 5% year-over-year which is maybe a third of the broader PC market. Do you guys have, you know, &#x2013; is there any reason to think that that at least catches up to PC market growth?  It seems to have actually been lagging and so, you know, is there a reason why we think that that can actually increase, or is this a case of things, like iPod, start picking up the slack as maybe the Mac installed base kind of shrinks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, not at all.  We would see each part of our product portfolio growing.  In the first quarter, our units were up 12%, reasonably close to the market growth rate.  This quarter they were up 5, but as I mentioned, we took channel inventory down.  So without getting into specific, our true sell-through was somewhat in between what we had in the first quarter sell-in versus what you see for this quarter.  So it's just slightly behind the market growth rate.  And really I think what's going on there is we are focused on growing our revenue, and not as focused on worldwide market share because we think that's misleading for us because we're not participating in every market around the world, and we're not participating on the low end of the desktop, which is seeing a lot of growth, but people don't seem to be making any money there.  However, in the markets that we are competing, we think that we're building momentum.  We gained about a point of market share in U.S. education in calendar year '03.  As Tim mentioned in the first half, our pro products are up 26% year-over-year, and we think we're gaining share in the consumer market that we &#x2013; in the consumer price bands that we are participating in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob.  Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Kevin Hunt with Thomas Weisel Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  I have a couple follow up questions.  You mentioned earlier the commodity prices as one of the benefits to gross margin.  I wonder if you could give us some kind of color or breakdown of that because it would seem that most of the components are actually pretty stable or up actually in price lately.  That's the first question.  And then the other question I just wanted to follow up on the balance sheet.  You said your inventory days were like four days, which was down I think a day from last quarter.  Where can you target &#x2013; is that a sustainable target going forward, the four days?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with your balance sheet question.  Yes, we were at four days this quarter, which was down from six days in Q1.  I'm not going to get into giving a specific target of where we think inventory will be except to say that we're generally carrying about two to three weeks of inventory in our stores, and we run our own distribution centers pretty lean.  And I'm sorry.  What was your first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the commodity prices, just give me some color.  You mentioned that was a benefit to the gross margin in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Are you asking about Q2, Q3 or both?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, the most recent quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Q2, we had a slightly better environment on LCDs that we had factored in but did not do quite as well on memory. But on balance we're certainly favorable to what we saw in Q1 and we're slightly better than what we had planned for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Now what are you &#x2013; and going forward, what's the outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, would you like to address that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, Peter.  Going forward on memory, we saw memory begin to climb in last quarter.  We view that that climb will continue in the early part of this quarter and then the things that we believe are driving that mainly I believe subside as the quarter moves on.  In panels, we saw panel pricing in general for notebooks fall across last quarter.  I think it reaches a kind of supply/demand equilibrium this quarter.  Monitor pricing went up slightly, but we are less affected by that because of the number of notebooks that we ship.</p>
          <p>The balance of the commodities we look to have reasonably normal declines and that's where we get the bulk of the component savings that Peter has spoken about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Actually two other quick things.  What was the number of stores that you said you had at the end of this quarter?  I think I missed that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>78.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>78?  And did you show how many iTunes you are at as of the end of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Downloads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you going to expose that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of weeks ago, we had said that we had sold our 50 millionth song and we will, from time to time, provide updates as we cross major milestones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kevin.  Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to David Sussman with Praxis Asset Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  I had a couple of questions about the reporting revenue and profits in the stores.  There's been some confusion about how the costs are allocated to the stores.  Can you elaborate on that, the costs of the, you know, the units sold, the software and the hardware?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  It's our &#x2013; our corporate policy is not to comment on pending litigation.  So I don't want to get into that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.  Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, ma'am.  Our next question is from Andrew Neff with Bear Stearns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the iTunes, I know you have gone into a lot of detail on that, but is iTunes additive to profitability at this point and any sense of what it could be going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  In the second quarter, we have a small profit on the Music Store.  Going forward, I'm not going to provide guidance, but future profitability would be dependent upon pricing and what the labels would charge us, volume, and what we invest to grow the store.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take a follow-up question from Rebecca Runkle with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Just a quick clarification question on the HP music units that will start shipping this summer.  I'm assuming that your commentary about reaching a supply/demand balance on iPod overall in the fiscal fourth quarter is inclusive of the HP products.  Can you confirm that?  And then also as it relates to your shipment schedule, have you had to scale back your volume to HP as a result of the supply/demand issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Beth, the deal with the HP is on the iPod, not the iPod mini.  HP and Apple might decide at a later date to include the mini, but we have not done that thus far, and as I've said earlier, we are today at a supply/demand balance on the iPod, and I don't anticipate that changing as we begin to ship to HP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fabulous.  Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Could we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question, a follow-up from Shannon Cross with Cross Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Just a very quick question.  In terms of, you had mentioned I think your warranty levels had gone back to more stable levels, which is one thing that helped the gross margin.  Did you reverse any of the warranty accrual that you took in the prior quarter, or &#x2013; you know, how does that reserve stand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we did not adjust that reserve back to income, and we are processing claims from customers as they come in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And any idea on how long you expect to continue to process claims and then I suppose there will be a true-up at some point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we still think our reserve is appropriate.  Tim, do you want to comment on either of the programs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I agree with what Peter said.  We always look at the reserve at the end of the every quarter to ensure that the number of claims that we've taken has been about what we expected, and we did that in the case that you're talking about, and we feel comfortable with what's provisioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks, Shannon.  Could we have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take a follow-up from Bill Fearnley with FTN Midwest Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.  Just a quick follow-up question on the eMac.  Are you folks looking at any potential margin hit from the new configurations announced earlier this week, especially with the new lower price on the 999 model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In general, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks very much to everyone.  A recording of today's call will be available for replay by telephone for seven days beginning at 5:00 p.m. Pacific time today and the number for the replay is 719-457-0820.  And the confirmation code is 496200.  A replay of the audio webcast of the call will be available beginning at approximately 5:00 p.m. Pacific time today at www.apple.com/investor and that will remain available for approximately 12 months.  Members of the press with additional questions can follow up with Steve Dowling at 408-974-1896.  Financial analysts can contact either Joan Hoover or me with additional questions.  Joan is at 408-974-4570 and I am at 408-974-5420.  Thanks again for joining us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude today's conference.  Thank you for your participation.  You may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>